Now that all the information has
been entered into the spreadsheet
and we've applied various
formatting to the information.
We've created a chart and linked
the data to other worksheets.
It's time to carry out some final
checks just to ensure that everything is
working OK, and it is fit for purpose.
So one of the first things we're
going to do is just carry out
a spelling and grammar check.
Unlike Word.
Excel does not automatically point out
that there was an error with spelling.
Normally in Word, you would get
a red lane or a blue line beneath
a piece of text, which would
indicate that it was incorrect.
Excel does not do that.
You would need to carry out a manual
check such as proofreading and then do
a manual spelling and grammar check.
So if I go to the review tab and
I've deliberately spelled a couple
of words wrong, so if I click on
the ABC spelling and grammar check,
and it will ask me, do I want to
continue checking and select "yes".
And it's already given me
two suggestions, so, yep.
So I want to change that to March
and it has also picked out the
second error, which was income.
So change that.
Yep.
And that should be the spelling
and grammar check complete.
As well as carrying out the spelling and
grammar check, it's always good to check
that all your formulas are accurate.
Now you could do this by simply checking
one of the formulas with a calculator.
So for example, the total sales, if
you added the January sales through to
the July sales together in a calculator
and it gave you the same figure, you
would know that the formula was correct.
As well as this, there are a range of
features on Excel that will allow you to
carry out some checks on your formulas.
So if I go to the formula
tab, click on that.
If I look along to the right there
is the formula auditing tools.
And what I can do is a variety of
tools here such as trace precedence.
So this simply tells me that if I
look at the total sales and select
trace precedents, it will tell me
what that formula is being made
up of, so it's sum of C2 to I2.
And I can see that the
trace precedence are there.
So those are what are making that up.
Or if I select remove arrows and
then select trace dependants, you
can also see that that figure there
is being collected and used within
the total income and the target met.
So that one is the trace precedents
and those two formulas within
there are dependent on that figure.
So that's another one I can do to
check that everything's working OK.
I can carry out, I'll just
remove the arrows there, I can
carry out some error checking.
The error check is complete
and that ensures that's OK.
So I'm happy with everything there.
And another tool I can use
is just to show the formulas.
So if I click on show formulas, it
will show me all the formulas that
have been used within that worksheet.
And then, if I go to the income
and again, I could see that all
of that data is linked correctly.
And again, with the average sales, if I
show formulas, it's show me the linked
data, as it is all linked to the sales
data worksheet and I'm happy with that.
For the chart one, I can right click
on the chart and click on select data
and that will show me that the data.
What the chart is being made from.
So again, I'm happy with that.
So once I've carried out all those checks,
I can go back, just undo the show formula.
Take that off there.
It's important to untick that because
once, if you saved it with the
show formulas still ticked or still
pressed, it will automatically save it.
So when anybody opens it, it will
automatically open in formula view.
So again, it's a case of just checking
through everything you may want to
apply some formatting so that the
formatting on the average sales is
consistent with the sales data worksheet.
So select everything in there, go to
the home tab, change the font to Arial,
apply some blue shading to that, and
then widen all of the columns, select
that button there, widen all the columns.
And I can even apply
borders to all of that data.
So select all borders.
And again, that just formats that
data so it looks more presentable
again, if I just check here.
Now, I don't want these to be showing
as any form of decimal place so I'll
just reduce those to whole numbers.
So again, that's OK there and on the
income, I'll do exactly the same.
So I'll change that to font too.
So again, if I select everything,
just click and apply the
formatting, all borders.
So I've now made the
worksheets consistent.
It looks fine there.
So now once I'm happy with
everything, I can save the
spreadsheet and then it is prepared,
ready to be shown to the audience.